A Finding Aid to the Adolph A. Weinman Papers, 1890-1959, in the Archives of American Art AAA.weinadol
Archives of American Art
Adolph A. Weinman papers
1890-1959
AAA.weinadol
Archives of American Art
9.7 Linear feet
The collection measures 9.7 linear feet, dates from 1890 to 1959, and documents the career of early twentieth century sculptor Adolph A. Weinman. Found within the papers are scattered biographical materials; project files for Weinman's sculpture and commissions; correspondence with colleagues, friends and family, and letterpress books containing copies of letters concerning specific sculpture commissions; files concerning Weinman's membership in the National Sculpture Society and the National Academy of Design; records concerning works of art held by dealers and in exhibitions and other miscellaneous financial materials; notes and a notebook; writings and speeches by Weinman; sketches and sketchbooks; printed materials; photographs and glass negatives. This material not only reflects the diversity of projects executed by this prolific sculptor, but illustrates the process of creation for many of his more important works.
Weinman, Adolph A.
Biographical Note
American sculptor, Adolph Alexander Weinman was born on December 11, 1870 in Germany and came to New York City in 1880. At the age of fifteen, he attended evening classes at Cooper Union. He later studied at the Art Students League. When he was twenty years old, he entered the studio of Philip Martiny and later worked with Olin Warner, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, Charles Henry Niehaus, and Daniel Chester French. In 1904, Weinman opened his own studio, and in the same year created the Destiny of the Red Man for the St. Louis Exposition. In 1923, he moved his studio to Forest Hills, New York, where he lived until his death.
Among Weinman's more notable sculpture commissions are the General Alexander Macomb Memorial in Detroit, Michigan, Alexander Johnston Cassatt and Samuel Rea for the Pennsylvania Railroad Terminal in New York City, the Seated Lincoln for Hodgenville, Kentucky, and sculptural group Riders of the Dawn at Brookgreen Gardens, South Carolina. In 1915, he designed The Rising Sun and Descending Night fountains for the Panama-Pacific Exposition in San Francisco. In the following year he designed the "Mercury" dime and "Walking Liberty" half dollar for the U. S. Mint. Weinman also created friezes for the U. S. Supreme Court building, and pediments for the National Archives building, the U. S. Post Office Department Building, and for the Jefferson Memorial, all in Washington, D. C.
Weinman was a member of many organizations, including the National Sculpture Society, of which he was president from 1927 to 1930, the American Academy of Arts and Letters, the National Institute of Arts and Letters, the National Academy of Design, and the New York City Art Commission.
Adolph A. Weinman died on August 8, 1952, in Port Chester, New York.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of American sculptor Adolph Weinman measure 9.7 linear feet and date from 1890 to 1959. Found within the collection are scattered biographical materials; project files for Weinman's sculpture and commissions; correspondence with colleagues, friends and family, and letterpress books containing copies of letters concerning specific sculpture commissions; a substantial body of files concerning Weinman's membership in the National Sculpture Society and the National Academy of Design; records concerning works of art held by dealers and in exhibitions and other miscellaneous financial materials; notes and a notebook; writings and speeches by Weinman; sketches and sketchbooks; printed materials; photographs and glass negatives. This material not only reflects the diversity of projects executed by this prolific sculptor, but illustrates the process of creation for many of his more important works.
Much of the collection (6.0 linear feet) consists of project files documenting many of Weinman's sculpture and commissioned public and architectural pieces through correspondence, contracts, financial records, notes, drawings, printed material, and photographs. A complete list of each project or sculpture file is found in the Container Listing. Also found are scattered biographical materials, general correspondence, files relating to Weinman's membership in the National Sculpture Society and the National Academy of Design, scattered financial files, notes and writings, art work, printed materials, and photographs.
Arrangement
Most materials have been arranged in chronological order, except for artwork and photographs which are arranged primarily according to subject matter. Glass plate negatives from the Project Files Series and Photographs Series have been removed and housed separately in Boxes 10-13 and are so noted in the Series Description/Container Listing Section at the appropriate folder title. Oversized material from various series has been housed in Box 14 and OV folders 15-22 and are listed with each appropriate series.
The collection has been arranged into 10 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1890-1950 (Boxes 1, 14, OVs 15, 22; Reel 5884; 4 folders)
Series 2: General Correspondence, 1897-1954 (Boxes 1-2, OV 15; Reels 5884-5886; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 3: Organization Files, 1916-1952 (Boxes 2-3; Reels 5886-5887; 0.9 linear feet)
Series 4: Financial Material, 1910-1953 (Box 3; Reel 5887; 3 folders)
Series 5: Notes, 1918-1952 (Box 3; Reel 5887; 14 folders)
Series 6: Writings, 1929-1952 (Box 3; Reel 5887; 14 folders)
Series 7: Artwork, 1892-1933 (Boxes 3, 14, OVs 16-19; Reels 5887-5888; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Project Files, 1896-1955 (Boxes 3-8, 10-14, OVs 15-22; Reels 5888-5891; 6.0 linear feet)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1891-1959 (Box 8, OV 21; Reel 5892; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, 1903-1950 (Boxes 9, 13, OV 21; Reel 5892; 0.2 linear feet)
Provenance
The Adolph A. Weinman papers were donated by Weinman's sons, Howard K. Weinman in 1972, and Robert A. Weinman in 1976.
Separated Material
In 1971 and 1972, Howard and Robert Weinman loaned selected documents for microfilming that are only available on microfilm reels 283 and 414. The loaned material is not included in this finding aid. Reel 283 contains biographical materials, a contract, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, and miscellaneous printed materials, dating from 1888-1952. Correspondence exchanged between Weinman and the Corcoran Gallery of Art and the Medallic Art Company between 1930 and 1952 is available on microfilm reel 414.
Restrictions on Access
A digitized version of the microfilm of this collection is available online via the Archives of American Art website. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Alternative Forms Available
The papers of Adolph A. (Adolph Alexander) Weinman in the Archives of American Art were digitized in 2005 from 9 reels of microfilm, totaling 12122 images.
National Academy of Design (U.S.); National Sculpture Society (U.S.); Drawings; Photographs; Sculptors--New York (State)--New York--Interviews; Sculpture, American; Sketchbooks; Sketches
- Biographical Material, 1890-1950; Series 1; (Boxes 1, 14, OVs 15, 22; Reel 5884; 4 folders)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material consists primarily of membership certificates, including those from the National Academy of Design, National Institute of Arts and Letters, Art Commission of the City of New York, Commission of Fine Arts, Lincoln Fellowship of Southern California, and the Mayor's Committee for the Golden Jubilee of The City of New York. Also found are several award certificates and scattered legal documents pertaining to members of Weinman's family.
  - Curriculum Vitae and Diploma, 1890, 1946-1950 (Reel 5884, Frame 12-33)
  - Membership Certificates, 1906-1948 (Reel 5884, Frame 34-41)
  - Award Certificates, 1904-1931 (Reel 5884, Frame 42-47)
  - Family Records, 1934-1948 (Reel 5884, Frame 48-50)
  - Oversized Diploma and Certificates, 1890, 1906-1912; (see also Box 14, OV 15, OV 22) (Reel 5884)
  - Oversized Certificates, 1904-1948; (see also Box 14, OV 15, OV 22) (Reel 5884)
  - Oversized Certificates, 1910, 1930; (see also Box 14, OV 15, OV 22) (Reel 5884)
- General Correspondence, 1897-1954; Series 2; (Boxes 1-2, OV 15; Reels 5884-5886; 1.4 linear feet)
  Letterpress books of Weinman's outgoing letters and unbound letters exchanged with colleagues and family members. Arranged in chronological order, the letters often refer to miscellaneous projects, but are not organized according to project. Many of the letters in the Letterpress books are written on very thin tissue paper and are barely legible. Additional project-specific correspondence is organized with Project Files.
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, undated (Reel 5884, Frame 52-64)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1897-1905 (Reel 5884, Frame 65-78)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1907-1909 (Reel 5884, Frame 79-103)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1910-1911 (Reel 5884, Frame 104-120)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1912-1913 (Reel 5884, Frame 121-172)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1914-1916 (Reel 5884, Frame 173-239)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1917-1918 (Reel 5884, Frame 240-260)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1919-1920 (Reel 5884, Frame 261-292)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1921-1922 (Reel 5884, Frame 293-306)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1923-1924 (Reel 5884, Frame 307-337)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1925-1926 (Reel 5884, Frame 338-425)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1927 (Reel 5884, Frame 426-447)
  - Oversize Site Maps for Providence, Rhode Island Project (Letter Enclosure), 1927 (Reel 5884, Frame 448-449)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1927-1928 (Reel 5884, Frame 450-500)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1928-1929 (Reel 5884, Frame 501-533)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1930-1931 (Reel 5884, Frame 534-551)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1932-1934 (Reel 5884, Frame 552-630)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1935 (Reel 5884, Frame 631-728)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1936-1937 (Reel 5884, Frame 729-814)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1938-1939 (Reel 5884, Frame 815-905)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1940-1941 (Reel 5884, Frame 906-991)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1942-1943 (Reel 5884, Frame 992-1055)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1944-1945 (Reel 5884, Frame 1056-1124)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1946 (Reel 5884, Frame 1125-1245)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1947 (Reel 5884, Frame 1246-1331)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1948 (Reel 5884, Frame 1332-1408)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1949 (Reel 5884, Frame 1409-1447)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1950 (Reel 5884, Frame 1448-1521)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1951 (Reel 5885, Frame 13-71)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1952 (Reel 5885, Frame 72-144)
  - Unbound Chronological Letters, 1953-1954 (Reel 5885, Frame 145-166)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1912-1913 (Reel 5885, Frame 169-307)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1914 (Reel 5885, Frame 308-357)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1915 (Reel 5885, Frame 358-441)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1916 (Reel 5885, Frame 442-502)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1917 (Reel 5885, Frame 503-563)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1918 (Reel 5885, Frame 564-618)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1919 (Reel 5885, Frame 619-739)
  - Letterpress Book I, 1920 (Reel 5885, Frame 740-867)
  - Letterpress Book II, 1921 (Reel 5885, Frame 868-952)
  - Letterpress Book II, 1922 (Reel 5885, Frame 953-997)
  - Letterpress Book II, 1923 (Reel 5885, Frame 998-1040)
  - Letterpress Book II, 1924 (Reel 5885, Frame 1041-1078)
  - Letterpress Book II, 1925 (Reel 5885, Frame 1079-1141)
  - Letterpress Book II, 1926 (Reel 5885, Frame 1142-1227)
  - Letterpress Book II, 1927 (Reel 5885, Frame 1228-1316)
  - Letterpress Book II, January-July 1928 (Reel 5885, Frame 1317-1374)
  - Letterpress Book III, July-December 1928 (Reel 5886, Frame 13-48)
  - Letterpress Book III, 1929 (Reel 5886, Frame 49-134)
  - Letterpress Book III, 1930 (Reel 5886, Frame 135-179)
  - Letterpress Book III, 1931 (Reel 5886, Frame 180-235)
  - Letterpress Book III, 1932 (Reel 5886, Frame 236-269)
  - Letterpress Book III, 1933 (Reel 5886, Frame 270-332)
  - Letterpress Book III, 1934 (Reel 5886, Frame 333-352)
- Organization Files, 1916-1952; Series 3; (Boxes 2-3; Reels 5886-5887; 0.9 linear feet)
  Weinman's files documenting his membership in and presidency of the National Sculpture Society and his membership in the National Academy of Design.
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, undated (Reel 5886, Frame 355-360)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1916-1922 (Reel 5886, Frame 361-398)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1923 (Reel 5886, Frame 399-454)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1924-1929 (Reel 5886, Frame 455-472)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1932-1936 (Reel 5886, Frame 473-513)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Reel 5886, Frame 514-540)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Reel 5886, Frame 541-581)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Reel 5886, Frame 582-602)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Reel 5886, Frame 603-660)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1946 (Reel 5886, Frame 661-737)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1947 (Reel 5886, Frame 738-852)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Reel 5886, Frame 853-879)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Reel 5886, Frame 880-927)
  - National Sculpture Society Correspondence, 1952 (Reel 5886, Frame 928-946)
  - National Sculpture Society Notes, 1947, undated (Reel 5886, Frame 947-951)
  - National Sculpture Society Meeting Minutes, 1922-1946 (Reel 5886, Frame 952-974)
  - National Sculpture Society Meeting Minutes, 1947 (Reel 5886, Frame 975-1031)
  - National Sculpture Society Meeting Minutes, 1948 (Reel 5886, Frame 1032-1059)
  - National Sculpture Society Meeting Minutes, 1949 (Reel 5886, Frame 1060-1095)
  - National Sculpture Society Meeting Minutes, 1950 (Reel 5886, Frame 1096-1146)
  - National Sculpture Society Meeting Minutes, 1951 (Reel 5886, Frame 1147-1242)
  - National Sculpture Society Meeting Minutes, 1952 (Reel 5886, Frame 1243-1294)
  - National Sculpture Society Financial Records, 1923-1946 (Reel 5886, Frame 1295-1317)
  - National Sculpture Society Financial Records, 1947-1948 (Reel 5886, Frame 1318-1412)
  - National Sculpture Society Financial Records, 1949 (Reel 5886, Frame 1413-1478)
  - National Sculpture Society Financial Records, 1949 (Reel 5887, Frame 13-53)
  - National Sculpture Society Financial Records, 1950-1951 (Reel 5887, Frame 54-136)
  - National Sculpture Society Financial Records, 1952 (Reel 5887, Frame 137-180)
  - National Sculpture Society Clippings, 1928-1952 (Reel 5887, Frame 182-207)
  - National Sculpture Society Newsletters, 1936-1940 (Reel 5887, Frame 208-247)
  - National Sculpture Society Newsletters, 1942-1946 (Reel 5887, Frame 248-289)
  - National Sculpture Society Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1938-1945 (Reel 5887, Frame 290-333)
  - National Academy of Design Correspondence, 1923-1936 (Reel 5887, Frame 335-359)
  - National Academy of Design Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Reel 5887, Frame 360-393)
  - National Academy of Design Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Reel 5887, Frame 394-423)
  - National Academy of Design Correspondence, 1948 (Reel 5887, Frame 424-494)
  - National Academy of Design Correspondence, 1949 (Reel 5887, Frame 495-529)
  - National Academy of Design Correspondence, 1951 (Reel 5887, Frame 530-580)
  - National Academy of Design Meeting Minutes, 1948-1950; (2 folders) (Reel 5887, Frame 581-617)
  - National Academy of Design Financial Reports, 1949-1950 (Reel 5887, Frame 618-626)
  - National Academy of Design Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1936-1949 (Reel 5887, Frame 627-667)
- General Financial and Business Records, 1910-1953; Series 4; (Box 3; Reel 5887; 3 folders)
  A record book listing art work held by dealers and in exhibitions. There are also miscellaneous financial records not directly related to projects; additional financial documentation is located within the Project Files.
  - Record Book of Works at Dealers and in Exhibitions, 1916-1951 (Reel 5887, Frame 669-715)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1910-1953; (2 folders) (Reel 5887, Frame 716-761)
- Notes, 1918-1952; Series 5; (Box 3; Reel 5887; 14 folders)
  A notebook illustrating Weinman's studies in French. Also found are lists of art work, photographs, ideas for art work, as well as notes concerning the National Commission of Fine Arts, and miscellaneous notes.
  - Notebook on Studies in French, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 763-788)
  - Lists of Art Works, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 789-807)
  - Lists of Photographs, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 808-867)
  - Illustrated Ideas for Art Work, 1918-1947, undated; (8 folders) (Reel 5887, Frame 868-969)
  - Notes Concerning the National Commission of Fine Arts, 1931-1932; (2 folders) (Reel 5887, Frame 970-1054)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1930-1952 (Reel 5887, Frame 1055-1071)
- Writings, 1929-1952; Series 6; (Box 3; Reel 5887; 14 folders)
  Speeches and lectures written by Weinman, including "Commemorative Tribute to John Russell Pope," 1937, "Tribute to Anna Hyatt Huntington," 1947, and "Memorial to Charles Keck," 1952. Also included is a typescript by Archibald MacLeish, "The Power of the Spoken Word."
  - Typescripts of Speeches and Lectures by Weinman, 1929-1952, undated; (13 folders) (Reel 5887, Frame 1073-1251)
  - Typescript, "The Power of the Spoken Word," by Archibald MacLeish, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 1252-1267)
- Artwork, 1892-1933; Series 7; (Boxes 3, 14, OVs 16-19; Reels 5887-5888; 0.4 linear feet)
  This series consists of annotated sketchbooks and unbound sketches by Weinman. One etching by Emil Fuchs can be found at the end of the series.
  - Annotated Sketchbook of Geometric Forms, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 1270-1277)
  - Annotated Sketchbooks of Human Anatomy, Sketchbook I, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 1279-1302)
  - Annotated Sketchbooks of Human Anatomy, Sketchbook II, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 1303-1341)
  - Annotated Sketchbooks of Human Anatomy, Sketchbook III, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 1342-1368)
  - Annotated Sketchbooks of Human Anatomy, Sketchbook IV, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 1369-1387)
  - Sketchbook of Female Model, undated (Reel 5887, Frame 1388-1399)
  - Sketches of Human Anatomy, 1915, undated; (2 folders) (Reel 5887, Frame 1400-1485)
  - Sketches of Human Anatomy, 1915, undated; (7 folders) (Reel 5888, Frame 12-76)
  - Sketches of Figures, 1892, undated; (2 folders) (Reel 5888, Frame 77-115)
  - Sketches of Animals, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 116-129)
  - Sketches of Animals, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 141-148)
  - Sketches of Plants, 1930, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 130-140)
  - Sketches of Historical Costumes and Artifacts, 1933, undated; (2 folders) (Reel 5888, Frame 149-196)
  - Miscellaneous Unbound Sketches, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 197-234)
  - Etching by Emil Fuchs, 1922 (Reel 5888, Frame 235-236)
  - Oversize Sketches of Animal Studies, undated; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Sketches of Plant Studies, 1930, undated; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Sketches of Historical Costumes and Artifacts, 1933, undated; (see also Box 14) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Sketches of Human Anatomy, 1915, undated; (see also OV 16) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Sketches of Figure Studies, 1892, undated; (see also OV 17) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Sketches of Figure Studies, cont., 1892, undated; (see also OV 18) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Sketches of Animal Studies, undated; (see also OV 18) (Reel 5888)
  - Oversize Sketches of Historical Costumes and Artifacts, 1933, undated; (see also OV 18) (Reel 5888)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize Sketches, undated; (see also OV 19) (Reel 5888)
- Project Files, 1896-circa 1955; Series 8; (Boxes 3-8, 10-14, OVs 15-22; Reels 5888-5891; 6.0 linear feet)
  Numerous project files for commissioned work and other sculptures arranged chronologically, with undated ones arranged at the beginning of the series. In some instances the name of the project or work of art has been supplied by the processing archivist based on image/s found in the files; known titles of works of art appear in italics. The majority of the project files contain only photographs, but several also contain a variety of documents related to the project, such as correspondence, contracts, financial records, notes, drawings, printed material, and photographs.
  Also found within the series are numerous glass plate negatives housed separately and closed to researchers, most of which have prints in their respective files and are so noted with a See Also reference. Oversized materials are also housed separately and noted with See Also references.
  - Couple in Long Robes, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 241-242)
  - Angel Casting Out Male Figures, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 243-244)
  - Soldier and Sailor with Flag, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 245-246)
  - Winged Figure Balanced on Sphere with Flag, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 247-250)
  - Plaque with Two Mourning Cherubs, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 251-252)
  - Arch Flanked by Allegorical Figures, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 253-254)
  - Spandrel Figures Over Arch, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 255-257)
  - Boys Holding Symbols of Industry, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 258-260)
  - Water Urchin, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 261-265)
  - Lion, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 266-268)
  - Buffalo, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 269-272)
  - Eagle on Sphere, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 273-275)
  - Grave Memorial for William Kimball, Graceland Cemetery, Chicago, Illinois, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 276-279)
  - Cherubim, Edward Oliver Wolcott Memorial, Woodlawn Cemetery, New York, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 280-285)
  - Aphrodite, undated; (3 folders; see also Box 14) (Reel 5888, Frame 286-299)
  - Narcissus, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 300-303)
  - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 313-315)
  - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 304-312)
  - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 316-317)
  - Eventide Plaques and Lion Statue, Baltimore Museum of Art, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 318-321)
  - Relief Portrait of Col. James R. Slack, Vicksburg National Military Park, Mississippi, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 322-323)
  - Hoff Hall, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 324-325)
  - Through the Smoke of Battle, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 326-327)
  - Standing Lincoln with Hand on Lapel, undated; (see also Box 10) (Reel 5888, Frame 328-329)
  - Prison Ship Martyrs Monument Eagle, Brooklyn, New York, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 330-331)
  - Woman in Pearls, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 333-337)
  - Bust of Unidentified Woman I, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 338-339)
  - Bust of Unidentified Woman II (Thompson?), undated (Reel 5888, Frame 340-342)
  - Bust of Unidentified Man, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 343-349)
  - Bust of Amy Comstock, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 350-359)
  - Bust of Mrs. Quinton Mason, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 360-361)
  - Relief Portrait of Adelaide, undated (Reel 5888, Frame 362-364)
  - Portrait Medallion of Katherine Jane (daughter), undated (Reel 5888, Frame 365-367)
  - Bust of Kathy Brooks (granddaughter), undated (Reel 5888, Frame 368-371)
  - Portrait Medallion of Bobbie (son), undated (Reel 5888, Frame 372-373)